MAREIKE VAN WIE

DETAILS

(727) 710 9700 mareikevanwie@gmail.com

- LINKS -

Linkedin

- SKILLS -

Communication Skills
Leadership and Teamwork
Analytical Thinking
Microsoft Excel
SQL
Python

LANGUAGES

German

PROFILE

Young- professional data researcher with an eye for details and willingness to learn. Looking for career opportunities in the field of data analytics. Passionate about the intersection of technology and democracy. Great social and team work skills with five years of community organizing experience.

EXPERIENCE

Special Programs Coordinator at Public Ally at Dream in Green, Miami

November 2020 — September 2021

Worked on data analytics, database management and assisted the development of a waste recycling application. Participated in asset-based community organization trainings. Published article for Consortium for a Healthier Miami-Dade.

Co-Organizer at Queer Pride Groningen, Groningen

January 2019 — March 2020

Met with local government officials regarding planning, funding and permits, culminating in a demonstration of 1,500+ people in attendance.

Student Ambassador at Rijksuniversiteit Groningen, Groningen

October 2018 — January 2020

Represented the University at open days and meetings with prospective students

External Affairs Coordinator at Groningen Feminist Network, Groningen

August 2018 — October 2019

Co-organized weekly meetings, lectures and demonstrations, as well as providing support for general admin and grant applications.

EDUCATION

Data Analytics BootCamp, University of Miami, Miami

February 2022 — July 2022

Courses include Python, R, SQL, Tableau, JavaScript.

MA Digital Humanities, University of Groningen, Groningen

September 2019 — July 2021

Coursework included Python, SQL, Data and Society and Visualizing Data.

BA English Language and Culture, University of Groningen, Groningen

September 2016 — June 2019

Coursework included English Linguistics, Literature and Research Methods in Humanities. Presented thesis research at NASA's (Netherland's American Studies Association) annual conference.

COURSES

IBM Data Analytics, Coursera

January 2022 — July 2022

Humane Technology, Center for Humane Technology

March 2022 — July 2022